

Jaeyong Lee South Korean, Age 29

Väinö Auerin Katu 1 N 047, 00560, Helsinki, Finland

 $Mobile: +358 \ (0) 46 \ 577 \ 5140, E-mail: jaeyonglee 05@gmail.com, portfolio: \\ \underline{www.studiojaeyonglee.com}, Linked In: \\ \underline{brack the line of the$

https://fi.linkedin.com/in/jaeyonglee05

PROFILE

A User Experience designer based on user-centered and experience-driven design approaches throughout design researches and strategies. Has worked and participated in various design projects as mainly a visual communicator for user experience, user interface, data visualization, interaction design, and service design.

Selected as a full scholarship student by National Institute for International Education(NIIED) for his master's study. Currently working on his master thesis project with Philips for 'Visual communication for Behavior Changes – Smart Air'.

EDUCATION

LDOCATION		
Aug. 2014~Present	Aalto University, Master of Arts	Helsinki, Finland
	Collaborative and Industrial Design, School of Arts, Design and Architecture	
	- Concentrates on creating optimal user experience design(UX), user interface design(UI), and services various design researches and strategies.	ice design through
	- Studies emphatic, critical, strategic and technological skills in design processes.	
Jun.2015~Aug.2015	Aalto University, Master of Arts	Helsinki, Finland
	Information Technology Programme – Strategy and Experience Design - 4.25/4.5 scale	
	- Worked with Verohallinto, the Finnish Tax Administration in charge of whole tax issues in Finland, to make innovative and strategic changes on current Vero.fi. Presented design solutions rebuilding information structure of Vero.fi with the Life Event' concept at the end of the program.	
Mar. 2005~Feb. 2012	Hongik University, Bachelor of Fine Arts	Seoul, South Korea
	Visual Communication Design, Metal Art and Design	
	- Cumulative GPA: 4.04 / 4.5 scale; Merit-based Scholarship Recipient five times (Total €6,500)	
	- Served military service between Jul. 2006 and Jul. 2008 in South Korea ROK army headquarters.	

- Served military service between Jul. 2006 and Jul. 2008 in South Korea ROK army headquarters.			
EXPERIENCE			
Sep. 2015~Nov .2015	Philips	Singapore	
	Design Intern		
	 Participated in visual communication designs for Primary Care Project in healthcare busine UI design and Graphic designs for Town Hall Event projects. 	ess, Philips Singapore website	
	 Currently working with Philips to proceed a master thesis project related with visual common changes – Philips Smart Air Purifier. 	unication and behavior	
Apr.2015~Aug.2015	Aalto University	Helsinki, Finland	
	Teaching Assistant		
	- Responsible for building materials for a course brochure and presenting it on Collaborative and Industrial Design (CoID)		
	Website.		
	 Built visual designs for printed course brochures and a digital presentation while communicating with students, clients, and teachers who were involved in the programme, and managed all processes of summarizing the final deliverables which 		
	students created.	ng the illiar deliverables which	
Jan. 2012~Apr .2014	0100 Design Studio, product & interior design company	Seoul, South Korea	
	Visual Designer		
	- Designed trophies representing the EXPO 2012 YEOSU KOREA.		
	- Developed visual concepts of interior and furniture designs for the new library in Chonbuk National University through		
	design researches.		
Jan.2011~Dec.2011	KEIDA studio, a Design & Art group		
	Design Team Leader, Visual Designer		
	- Awarded Red Dot Concept Design Award 2012 through 'Traveler's Paper Kit'.		
	 Collaboration with Object, which was a project for designing eco-friend lightings through r Joined various design exhibitions including TETSUSON, Modern Haute Couture Exhibition 	recyclea materials.	
Jan.2011~Mar.2011	FS Korea LTD, cosmetic container design & production company	Seoul, South Korea	

- Designed cosmetic containers and carried out market design research

Product Design Intern

Fluent

Basic

English

Japanese

Visual Designer

- Developed visual designs for a short animation film, 'White Ball'.
- Developed color concepts of animation in 'Let's go MBA,' which was broadcasted on SBS.

AWARD & HONOR

Aug.2014	Selected as a full scholarship student by National Institute for International Educat	ion (NIIED) for
	2 years.	South Korea
	 Selected as a representative scholarship student in 2014 in South Korea by NIIED where runs by Korea and fully supported for master's degree studies for 2 years. 	ın Government,
Apr.2014	2014 Character & Marketing Design Award of LOTTE World Tower Mall, 3 rd prize - Winning work: Lopy, Mascot design of Lotte World Tower Mall and relevant applications design - Winning prize: € 2500	South Korea
Sep. 2013	2013 Red Dot Concept Design Award, Honorable Mention - Winning work: Life-Light, Emergency directional system for vulnerable people	Germany
Sep. 2012	2012 Red Dot Concept Design Award, Winner - Winning work: Traveler's Paper Kit, Emergency paper kit for travelers	Germany
Aug. 2012	Korea Good Design Award, Good Design Selection - Winning work: Triangle Gate, Optical electronic gate indicating obvious direction	South Korea
Nov. 2011	6th Recycling of Resource Junk Art Contest, Encouragement prize - Winning work: Spectacle #1, Junk Art using abandoned electronic devices and video	South Korea
Sep. 2008	Korean Association Against Drug Abuse Cartoon Contest, Excellence Award - Winning work: Too dangerous to touch, Message about dangerousness of drugs	South Kored
INTERVIEW		
Oct. 2012	Design So Ri - Article: 2012 Red Dot Concept Design Award winner: Lee, Jae Yong, Website: http://www.designsori.co	Online Publishing om
Sep. 2012	j.j magazine, - Design magazine, Article: Defined Monsters, Lee Jae Yong. I am a monster, p40~41	South Korea
Mar. 2012	Incubator - Design magazine, Article: Defined Monsters, p48~55	South Korea
Oct. 2011	Art Share - Article: Interview vol.02_Lee, Jae Yong, Website: http://www.artshare.kr	Online Publishing
TEACHING AC	TIVITY	
Jan. 2012~Oct. 2012	Clay Gim Art Institute Tutor	South Korea
Mar. 2005~Jul. 2006	- Private Art Institute for children from 5 to 10 Jeon Won Art Institute Tutor	South Korea
INTERFET	- Private Art Institute for art college prep students	
INTERESTS		1.
	Interests include animation film making (have directed two short animation films), learning and sports such as badminton and football.	g coding
SKILLS	and sports sacinas badimition and football.	
Excellent	Adobe Creative Suite, Digital prototyping tools, Animation making tools	
Good	MS Office	
Basic	CAD, Rhino, Dream weaver, HTML, CSS	
LANGUAGE		
Mother tongue	Korean	

Jaeyong Lee